Agustin Guerra

888-858-6716 | agustinguerra@ufl.edu | LinkedIn | Website

Professional Profile

Highly motivated engineering professional with 5+ years of experience in the transportation industry. Committed to providing high-quality service focusing on innovation, safety, sustainability, operational performance, diversity, equity, and inclusion. Currently pursuing a PhD degree in Civil Engineering.

EDUCATION

PhD candidate in Civil Engineering

University of Florida, GPA: 3.66

MS in Civil Engineering

University of Kansas, GPA: 3.89

BS in Civil Engineering

Universidad Tecnologica de Panama

Aug. 2019 - Expected May 2023

Gainesville, FL

Aug. 2017 - May 2019

Lawrence, KS

Mar. 2008 – May 2013

Panama, PA

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Expertise: Transportation Engineering, Statistical Analysis, Operation Research, Machine Learning

Languages: Python (Proficient), R (Intermediate)

Software: VISSIM, HCS, AutoCAD Civil 3D, Infraworks, Slide-Rockscience

Developer Tools: Github, Visual Studio

Libraries: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, CPLEX

EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant

Aug. 2019 - Present

Gainesville, FL

University of Florida

- Develop optimization algorithms in Python for arterials considering automated-vehicles capabilities
- Assist in the implementation of optimization algorithm for isolated intersections
- Facilitated the coordination of project activities to meet deadlines
- Explained traffic flow theory assignments to students

Highway & Traffic Consultant

May 2019 - Aug. 2019

Panama

- Provided safety assessment for roadways, interchanges, and intersections
- Developed geometric design proposals
- Conducted earthwork estimation for highway projects

Highway Engineer

Nov. 2012 - Aug. 2017

Louis Berger

WSP

Panama

- Developed geometric designs for proposal and as-built drawings for highway projects. Project portfolio comprises several projects in the Latin American region (Panama, Colombia, Honduras, and Peru) adding up to \$3 billion in construction amount
- Coordinated with different departments (geotechnical, hydraulic, and pavement) to meet deadlines
- Created digital model terrain for highway projects
- Verified slope stability analysis using the Slide-Rockscience software
- Supervised and mentored drafter team with 4 people

LEADERSHIP/INVOLVEMENT

Volunteer at the Young Member Council, TRB: Currently developing a website for the YMC - $S\&R$	2022 – Present
Co-founder of the IEEE-ITS Student Chapter: Currently leading the efforts to establish an IEEE Student Chapter focused on ITS	2022 – Present
ITE University Chapter Vice President: Coordinated student seminars and $\underline{\text{ITE}}$ activities	2021 - 2022
Student Representative at the UFTI Internal Steering <u>Committee</u> : Promoted engagement activities between industry professionals and students	2020 - 2022
Media Manager at KU Fulbright Student <u>Association</u> : Led dissemination of activities promoted by the Fulbright Student Board, 2018	2018 - 2019

Fellowships & Awards

ITS Florida Anne Brewer Academic Scholarships: Awarded by the ITS Florida Chapter	2022
Fulbright Fellowship: Awarded by the U.S Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs	2017
Global Best Project: Awarded by the ENR for the Coastal Beltway project in Panama	2015
Relevant Projects	
4th Bridge over the Panama Canal Panama	2019
 Provided visibility and safety assessment for intersections and roadways 	
• Developed geometric design alternatives for interchanges	
• Construction cost: \$1.2 billions	
Corredor Panama Norte Panama	2016
• Played a major role in the coordination of the project	
 Developed design drawings and calculations including 3D models of roadways, roundabouts, and int Provided earthworks estimation 	terchanges
Perimetral Oriental de Bogota Colombia	2015
• Coordinated with other departments (geotechnical, hydraulic, surveying) to meet deadlines	
• Developed design drawings and calculations including 3D models of roadways, intersections, and int	erchanges
• Trained and supervised drafter team	
• Construction cost: \$428.0 millions	
Panamerican Highway Widening Santiago -Vigui Panama	2014
• Provided design alternatives including 3D models and drawings for intersections	
• Analyzed the slope stability of critical sections	
• Construction cost: \$340.0 millions	
Corredor Turistico La Barca – El Progreso – Tela Honduras	2014
 Conceived design drawings for roundabouts and urban sections including sidewalks, and bus-stops Provided traffic signs drawings using the MUTCD and local guidelines 	
• Construction cost: \$120.0 millions	
Slope Stabilization Studies 53 km Panama	2014
• Interpreted the slope stability analysis results	2014
• Examined ground improvement alternatives	
• Construction cost: \$0.4 millions	
Amador Causeway Widening Panama	2014
• Assisted with the geometric design of roundabouts	
• Participated in the creation of the digital terrain model	
 Assisted with the modeling of critical sections for embankments stability analysis 	
• Construction cost: \$95.0 millions	
Coastal Beltway Panama	2012
• Developed design drawings for roadways including roundabouts, marine viaducts, and interchanges	
• Construction cost: \$ 45 millions	
Professional Societies	
<u>IEEE</u> : Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers	2022 - Present
ASCE: American Society of Civil Engineers	2022 - Present
<u>ITE</u> : Institute of Transportation Engineers	2019 – Present
References	
Lily Elefteriadou, PhD: Barbara Goldsby Professor, University of Florida el	lefter@ce.ufl.edu

Lily Elefteriadou, PhD: Barbara Goldsby Professor, University of Florida Aurora Izquierdo: Civil Structural Engineer II, WSP Juliana Canas: Senior Advisor, First Climate Julio Aysa: Env./Social and Governance Lead Officer, IDB

elefter@ce.ufl.edu Aurora.Izquierdo@wsp.com juliana.canas-vanegas@firstclimate.com jaysa71@yahoo.com.mx